Today we are comparing ICICI Potentials I
Protect Smart Plus and Aditya Birla
Super Term Plan.
Mahavir Chopra is the Founder and Chief
Executive Officer of Beshak.org.
The Eligibility Criteria You can get the
ICICI Pash plan up to a maximum age of 60
years.  Meaning basically you are above 60 years of age.
After that you cannot take this term plan.
So Aditya Billa's plan is
basically a Super Term Plan, the maximum
entry age in it is 65 years.  Typically
you should not buy a term plan at this age.
You should buy a term plan much earlier; it should
basically be in the age group maximum
before 40-45 years of age.  So this is not a
very big blocker in my.  Now moving on to
the other customization options that are
available.  Maturity age.  Maturity age
means when you are buying the plan, how long should this
plan last?  Till what age should this
plan be active right to be able to cover
you.  Right?  This is what we are understanding.
So in case of ICICI potential iProtect
Smart Plus you
can run this plan till the age of 99 years.  In case of Aditya
Birlas plan it is 85 years.  This means that
if you are taking a plan at the age of 30, then
your plan can remain active till you are 85 years old
and your cover can continue.
Right?  This is what we are
understanding.  In this you can obviously have less whatever
between 85 you can
reduce it 84 83 whatever is available as an
option.  But this is the maximum that you can do.
Right?  Now moving on to the sum
assured options.  What sum assured
options are available?  Both in case of ICICI
Prudential and Aditya Birla the minimum sum
insured that one has to take is Rs 50 lakh.   The
maximum sum insured in case of ICICI
potential is not specific, it is something that is
case to case basis depending on your
profile depending upon the case and
depending upon the insurance company's
policies.  In case of Aditya Birla Super
Term Plan it is Rs 25 crore.  This means that
you cannot buy a term insurance plan above Rs 25 crore.
This one is Aditya Birla
Super Term Plan.  Claim Payout Option There
is a lot of options as to how the claim will be paid when it is paid.  How will it get
paid?  Now the most default option that most of us
know is that a big lumpsum amount lands in the
bank account of the nominee.  But there are
customizations that are available.  What are the
customizations that are available.  One is that you
can break it down so that you get a lump sum
that covers all the loans.  All the major
responsibilities should be paid and then the
rest should be converted into income.  The second
option available is basically
that your entire money gets
converted into monthly income.  Meaning, typically the
option available is divided into 100 months
and paid to you.
So if you have a cover of Rs 1 crore, then it is
paid to you in lakhs of rupees.
There is one option that is
available.  Some companies offer something which is called
increasing monthly cover.  Because there is
inflation, so ₹1 lakh is good today.
₹1 lakh may be reduced in the next year also.  So
increasing monthly come on option is also available.
Monthly income option is also available.  ICICI
potentially offers all these four options that
I told you.  Lumpsum Option, Level Monthly
Income Option means Fixed Monthly Income
Option.  Increasing Monthly Income Option and
Lumpsum Plus Level Monthly Income Option i.e.
Fixed Monthly Income Option, all these four are available.
Only the Increasing Monthly Income option is
not available in Aditya Birla Super Time Term Plan.  The remaining three are available.
Early Exit Option: This is also a very
interesting thing that you bought Term and Chance.
Late you said that whatever
is the maximum age, right 85, 99, whatever it is, you have
taken the entire cover till then.  You have
purchased a plan for up to 85 years.  But now you are paying
premium every year.  Your net worth has become
such that you actually do
not need term insurance right now.  At Let's Say
a Particular Edge.  You feel that now you do not need
a term insurance cover because you have
accumulated enough well.  Insurance companies
have now started giving you an option
where you can exit from the term
insurance plan and then the cover will stop
and you will basically be returned the
premium.  Now ah get 100 if I
read to you what is written here then you will
understand it a little better.  Get 100% premium back if
you choose to discontinue before
maturity.  This can be done during a
specific time frame.  It is not like
you pay premium for 5 years and then you
can stop and you will get all the premium
back.  The idea behind the insurance company is
that basically they are
trying to mirror your own accumulation of
wealth that after a period of time if you feel that now
you have enough wealth and you do not need
term insurance how they can basically
help you with an early exit and getting
your money back to you.  Right?  So that is what is
basically the effort here or the ah what they are
trying to do here.  So typically in
case of ICICI potential the option is when
can you exercise this option when you are
60 years old and above, if you have crossed 60 years then
you can do it
and basically the option is completion of 25
years but cannot be exercised during the
first last five years of the policy so
25 years must be completed.  So, if
you have bought the policy at the age of 40, then it
means that your 25 years will be at 65, but
that will not be possible.  You will have to do it at the age of 60.
So
you have to exercise this option at the age of whichever is lower.
You cannot exercise this option in the last five years.
If you have taken a policy of 75, then
in the last five years your age will become 70,
but the maximum in this is 60, so
60 will be the lowest age at which you will be
able to exercise this option. Now let's look
at Aditya Birla how this option is offered.
In case of Aditya Birla, you can opt
for this option between the age of 60 to 70
years, right, that is what you can do when you can
opt for this option and the completion is
where we talked about 25 years, here the
completion is 30 years, before that you cannot do it,
your premium payment for 30 years has been done,
then ah, no premium payment,
your term of 30
years has been completed, only then you can exercise this option.  Let us take
an example that
I bought a policy at the age of 25 years.  30
years is 55 years.  Right?  At the age of 55, I can
basically say that hey guys, I don't need this
plan anymore.  I
want to exit early and I want my
premium back.  Then the insurance company will
return your premium back.  The interesting
thing in this is that this return of premium
option is not just an option.
Your premium is not changing in this.
So there is a term return of premium option.
Your premium increases in what is called a trope.  This is
typically an option that is available at the
same premium that you are getting this option
in the same term plan that is available in the
market.  Right?  So this is why it became
interesting compared to the TROP
option that was earlier available.  Now Moving
On To Live Stage Option.  Live Stage Option
means that when you buy term end on, at
that time you have bought the
term plan by doing a specific calculation
that how much cover is required.  But your
responsibilities may increase.  Like
you might get married.  You took a home loan.
You need cover for that.  I have children and
need cover for them.  For that you have to
increase the cover.  But term insurance
typically does not allow any kind of
upgrades.  You can upgrade to Help Insurance.  You
cannot upgrade to this.
So what will you do?  One option is the
Lifestage option, which you can opt for, but which you do not have to
opt for. It is available
as part of the plan.  In this, on
specific events like marriage, child
birth and home loan you will get specific
increase of sum insured that is available to
you.  You can you have to request for it.
In this you have to pay the premium.  But the
advantage in this is that you will be upgraded to this same plan.
How much
is available?  In ICICI potential case,
your time for marriage can increase by 50%.
Your tax may increase by 25% for child birth.
100% sum assured for home loan may increase.
Suppose you have taken a cover of Rs 2 crore, then
basically in normal cases it can be Rs 4 crore.
Right?  In case of child birth,
your cover can increase by 25% on Rs 2 crore i.e. Rs 50 lakh.
In this,
in the case of ICICI Prudential, it is mentioned that underwriting will be required.
So, whenever you take this, if you choose this
option, the insurance company will make you
fill a form and check whether it
can give you this update or not.   It
is very important to understand.  In Aditya Birlas's
Super Term Plan, 50% is available
for marriage capped at 50 lakh, child birth
25% capped at 25 lakh and home loan 50% capped
at 50 lakh. So, there is a cap in this, in its case there
is no cap in IC potential.
Interestingly, but Aditya Birla is
giving an interesting thing that no fresh
medical underwriting will be required.
Basically, it means that after you have taken the plan, if
you face any health issues or medical
conditions, that will not be the reason why you will
not get an upgrade, you will still get an upgrade. There will be no
basic underwriting at all, there will be no
medical related underwriting. That is what is
mentioned
in the policy wordings.  Next is
terminal illness.  Terminal illness means
that during the term of the plan if the
person is basically diagnosed with the
terminal illness.  Terminal illness means
that the illness is such that the
person will pass away.  Right?  Meaning there are certain
diseases and conditions where the person
basically will pass away.  The typical one I
remember is cancer.  Right?
When does cancer occur? Sometimes this third stage cancer is
a terminal illness.  So if terminal
illness happens then what are the options that are
available?  Both the plans offer something.  A.
ICICI Protential provides you with accelerated
cover.  This means that before
your death, the money basically goes to whoever is taking this plan.
So what is the benefit of that, that
I can give money to whomever I want to give it with my own hands.  If
I have taken this cover.  In case of Aditya
Vilas Super Term Plan 50% of the death
benefit.  You can accelerate and take the money first.
So lately I am this person and
this has happened to my terminal.  So I
took 50% cover of Rs 5 crore.  For
example, I can opt to get Rs 2.5 crore in advance.
And I
can decide how to distribute it with my
own hands.  That is the whole idea of
basically terminal benefit.  Ok?  So the next thing that we are
comparing is increasing
cover options.  Like I said that typically term
insurance does not allow upgrades.  But there are certain
options that are available, one that is
already mentioned is the live stage
option.  The second is increasing cover option.   Which gives you
a way of systematically
increasing your cover.  Why would you choose this?
When you are taking cover, you have an
eligibility.  According to that eligibility,
you are getting some cover.  But you know that as
your responsibility is increased in the
future you will need more cover.  So you could
systematically decide today that you want an
increasing cover.  Now typically what is the
option that is available in case of ICI Protected
Eye Protect Smart Plus.  You
can increase your cover by 10% every
year.  Right?  There is one thing mentioned in this which
I actually did not understand.  But still
I will tell you because it is my job to
tell you here.  Cover can increase up
to 145% of the base cover.  Now this is something which does
not add up in any way.  But
probably by the time we publish this
video we will have that clarification we will put it in
the description that is what is
mentioned in case of Aditya Birla Super Term
Plan the cover can increase by 5% every year
up to 100% of base cover means whatever your
cover is, if you take a cover of 1 crore it will become 1 crore 5 lakhs, by doing so
your cover will keep increasing
up to 100% means up to 2 crores so that is what is
increasing cover looking at the
riders there are three specific riders which we will
try to understand quickly accidental
death rider means if someone has
taken a term plan then he will get a specific cover in case of natural death
which is basically a cover of 2 crores so he will
get 2 crores if accidental death happens then
additional cover is available.  Additional
amount is paid to the family.  Right?  So I am
telling you what is typically available.
Accidental Death Rider is available up to 85
years in case of I Protect Smart
ICICI and Super Term Plan
in Aditya Birla which is available up to 80 years.   The
maximum cover available in case
of ICICI Potential is Rs 3 crore.  In case
of Aditya Birla it is 2 crores but
obviously subject to the higher your sum
insured.  You will not get 100% of the sum insured.
Meaning you will not get more than double.  If
your base sum insured is Rs 1 crore, you will
get Rs 2 crore.  Ah, even if your base is Rs 3 crore, you will still
get only Rs 2 crore.  Right?  That is what you have
to understand.  Next is the
critical illness rider.  Critical Illness is
one such rider that people should typically take
but they do not have much information about it.
Typically today the way we live, the
kind of life that we live, it is very very, all the
people who are 25-30 years old and are
watching this video, they need to understand the way
medical science is
progressing.
Motility means how long a person will live.
Life longevity is increasing.
Like it's not going to be that
typically, it's a lot of studies say that people who are
25 years old today will live more than
100, right?  The reason for that is basically
medical science.  Right?  So typically the kind
of life that people will live and the kind of
medical science will available to you will live for
100 years.  But unfortunately because of
lifestyle issues, because of sedentary
lifestyle, because of pollution, what of
other things like stress, there will be
critical illnesses that everybody will also
face at their later ages.  Right?  So,
what is the main problem of critical illness?
One of the health insurance
related expenses of critical illness is that you will have to bear the
hospitalization expenses.  All this
happens.  He will cover health insurance.
But there is also loss of earnings where
you start earning less than what you were earning.
Because the amount of time and effort that you were
able to give, you are
not able to give after suffering from a critical illness.
You might be wondering what does critical illness
mean?  This is a very technical
term.  Critical illness means that
someone has a major illness like for example
paralysis, heart attack,
cancer.  All these things that happen are
major illnesses.  Where your
life gets a little shake up.  You ca
n't do as much work as you could before.
You get one type of compensation for one type of it.  Let us
understand what kind of compensation is available in this.  The
rider that ICICI Potential is offering is
called Comprehensive Rider.  This means that
you are getting this separate sum insured.
Your sum insured, your term insurance, has nothing to do with it.
Whatever you are
taking in this, you are getting additional cover.
In this you are getting the option of two types of illnesses.
Meaning you are getting a set of options.
You are a little too much for what I am
telling you.  But it is very
important to tell because this is a very important cover.
You can cover 60 illnesses or another
option is available in which you
can cover 20 illnesses.  According to me, 20
illnesses is good enough but 60 obviously gives
you more psychological comfort.   The
maximum age by which you can cover is 75
years.  This means that after 75 years this cover will be
closed.  Even if you are
taking a policy for 80 years, the term
policy you are taking will be closed at 75.   The
cover available is minimum Rs 10 lakh and
maximum Rs 1 crore.  You will get a lump sum of Rs 1 crore.
If there is a critical illness,
your family will get a maximum lump sum of Rs 1 crore.
Now let us understand
what Aditya Birla is and let us explain it
in more detail.  So let us understand this.
Aditya Birla gives you a comprehensive option
which is basically that you will have a separate cover
or gives you an accelerated option.
Accelerated means that it will give you money by
taking out your own term insurance cover from it.
So, if you have
taken a cover of Rs 2 crore late, a
portion will be taken out from it and given to you first if you have a
critical illness.  So there are two options in this also.
If you are taking a comprehensive rider, then
four illnesses will be covered.  This
means that if you are taking separate cover then
four illnesses will be covered.  If you are
taking accelerated option in which
you are withdrawing money from the cover of your term insurance itself, then
it is called accelerated option.
It will cover 42 illnesses.
So you are
getting a more comprehensive cover in case of
Aditya Birlas Accelerated CI
Rider.  Right?  The maximum age covered is
70 years.  The minimum cover that you can get in
Comprehensive CI Rider is Rs 75,000.
In Accelerated CI Writer, Rs 5 lakh is the
minimum cover which obviously should be this much.  There was
no point in taking less than this.  The
maximum cover you can opt for is 50
lakhs
in both the cases in case of Comprehensive
CI Rider and in case of Accelerated CI
Rider subject to 100% of the sum assured.
So it is obvious that it will not be more than your main sum assured.
Waiver of
Premium Rider.  Waiver of Premium Rider
is also a rider that if you suffer from any type of
critical illness or permanent
disability, you cannot pay further premiums.
So if you take this rider
then typically the future premiums after that
critical illness has happened and the
accidental disability has happened are
waived you don't have to pay the premiums but
your cover remains intact what is that is
offered by both these plus in case of ICICI
potential this is an option that is available up
to the age of 75 years.  Critical Illnesses
Covered There are 15 critical illnesses
covered.  If you suffer from any of the 15 critical illnesses,
you will not be required to pay premiums after that even if you take this rider for a minimum term of 15 years and do not take the critical illness rider.
You basically do
not have to pay any premium.  Your cover will continue.  In the
case of Aditya Birla Sum Sun plan,
basically four illnesses are covered.
In case of ICIC potential it is 15
illnesses that are covered.  But whatever I
mentioned in terms of the benefit is the same.
Now we move to exclusion.  So,
understand that exclusion is a lot.  Because there are many
websites of insurance companies
which say that there are
seven types of deaths out of eight types which are not covered.
Variant for us to take a break here
and make you explain this that term
insurance as a contract does not have
any exclusion except one exclusion
which is suicide and that is only for the
first year.  There is no type exclusion after that.
Term insurance
covers all kinds of death.  Please
understand this.  These are the details,
these are the things, these are the important things
, no one can tell them typically.  Because
everyone tells you some things after reading SEO articles or SEO
means if SEO has become a little technical then after
reading website articles.
An expert can tell you this in a better
way.  Experts are
people who have
made a career in this field on a regular basis.  They make
people understand the policy, explain it to them and then
sell it to them.  Stand by them at the time of claims.
Stand with their families.  We
ensure that the claim is
settled equally.  You should buy term insurance from such people.  You should
buy it with understanding.
All these nuances should be understood before
purchasing.  If you
want to basically consult such experts then of course they get
you consulted for free.  There is a link to such
experts in the comments and in the
description.  By
using it you can initiate your consultation
with us.  Now Moving On
To Customer Service.  They understand whose customer service is
good.  So toll free
icic potential has been marked as
quick.  Aditya Bilal has also marked as
quick.  So both are very good on toll free.
This is basically what is coming out compared
to all other companies in the market.
Response time on Twitter ICICI potential
is marked as slow means not good fast
response not so good response.
Aditya Birla is average right so
Aditya Birla is doing decent but as good as bad as any
other company.  Now Moving On
To Claims Experience.  It is very important to
understand the claims experience because
obviously you take insurance claims.
Speed ​​of claim settlement.  Speed ​​of
claim settlement means that if a company
receives 100 claims, then
understand how many claims it settles in the first 30 days.
So it is 98.15%.
In case of Aditya Birla, the ICIC potential is 99.98%.
Meaning it basically is almost all claims are
settled in the first 30 days.  Great.  It's a
good number.  ICICI potential is also not
bad.  Of course claim complaint 0.07% in
case of ICICI potential 0.02% in case of
Aditya Birla.  Again Aditya Birla is
taking a lead here.  Claim settlement
ratio.  I
typically do not give much importance to this ratio because
this ratio does not tell you actually the
experience that you will get at the time
of claim.  But still because a lot of people
keep asking us about it.  I am just
sharing it with Claim Settlement Ratio
Number of Claims 99.31% in case of IIC
Potential 98.65% in case of Aditya Birla
Claim Settlement Ratio Value of Claims
This is very high because whatever claims a company is
giving, a question
comes to many people that whether the insurance
company settles big claims or not, this
ratio tells us that.  In case of
ICICI potential is 98.06%,
in case of Aditya Birla it is 96.22%,
so this ratio of Aditya Birla is a bit poor.
This means that
Aditya Birla is probably rejecting bigger claims
compared to smaller claims.  There are many
facilities that life insurance
companies offer at the time of claims which are very
important to understand. They are
offering a lot of facilities which makes
your family's life a little easier at the time
of claims service.
So ICICI potential gives you a
dedicated toll free number.  Where
you can just follow for claims.
You can track your claims
online.  Where do you basically have a claim?
You will know what the status is.
Provides home pickup of claims.  This means that you and
your family will not have to go
to the branch or stand
in a queue for the claim.  Family means someone from your family will
come and pick up the claims.  Personal
relationship manager is also available.  Meaning they will
basically help you from the time
you initiate the claim to the time the claim
is paid is what is promised by ICICI
Bank.  Compare to Aditya Birla Super
Term, only they are providing the facility to track the claim online.  They are
not giving
a dedicated toll free number.  Which is
not a very big deal because you have to call the
regular number and press to for
claims.  So it's not a very big
problem but giving a dedicated free
dedicated toll free number basically shows that
you want to gives a little more importance to the
claim customer right home pickup is not given to
you personal relationship manager Aditya
Birla.
Aditya Birla has not launched this service yet.  You will
basically get this service in ICICI Potential.  Let
us also try to understand how complicated a claim form is.
Because it gives you an
understanding of the intent of the company at
the time of claims.  Weather they want to basically ask you
many questions before they give
you the claim and they make it very
simple.  There are some companies that
simplify the forms a lot.  Because their
main goal is to ensure that
whatever questions you had to ask at the time of claim have been
asked at the time of giving the policy.  Now at the
time of claim, they
want to give you the claim by asking minimum questions.  There are some
companies that make very long claim forms.
That to me personally and to us as a
company also collectively we don't feel that is a
good thing to basically ask a lot of
questions to the family at the time of
claims because the family has no one here to
take the benefit of the investment that the
person who is not anymore has done.  Right?  So
the firm should be very simple.  Unfortunately,
in the case of ICICI Productions and Aditya
Burra, both have very long train
forms compared to all the other companies
that we have researched.  So this is a little
big of a red flag.  But
I have seen that in most of the private companies, the
forms are long.
Basically, they have to pay the claim only after some more investigation.
Understand pricing.  Pricing is very important obviously because it could typically completely
change your view about which plan to
take and which not to take.  Because the plan is very simple.
You are getting a cover at a sum insured.
And the exclusions are very simple in
that there is an exclusion for suicide in the first year,
after that there is no exclusion.  It's a
kind of a commodity to a certain extent,
only the service obviously makes the difference
and the experience makes the difference.  The cover
is typically a commoditized cover.  So let's
look at what is the difference in the premium.
Premium for a 30 year old male
living in Mumbai.  2 crore sum insured.  A
term of 40 years.  Meaning he is taking the policy till the age of 70 years
and on regular pay, meaning he is
not taking any type of limited option.
Pay option.  A premium for ICIC
potential in the first year is 18,582
while we are recording this video.  22355
from the year two.  So, some
discounts are available in the first year which are
not available in the second year.  You can consider the
premium as ₹2,355.  In case of Aditya
Birla Super Term Plan the premium is
significantly high.  There is a huge difference in
premium.  ₹39,651
almost double the premium of ICICI
potential which is a typically makes it to
me it makes it a kind of a raw deal.  Meaning, there must be a
very strong reason for someone to make such a huge difference.  Ah but there
is a huge difference in the premium.  Am what we have
understood so far
in claim service I have seen that Aditya Birla has done a
great job that is one difference I could find but otherwise I could not see any
major difference all the other things are
customization that is 1920 between both the companies let's understand
rating it is important to
understand this because we stock all the plans we have a
sister concern brand of
Bech which is called ILM Research which does very very detailed
comparison of all the plans that are available in
the market and rates the things which are most important to the
customers and each company
rates all the 150-100 term plans available in the market then from that
you get to know
where this plan stands and all the plans in the
market.  So that is what we have tried to
understand in case of product benefit the
rating that ICICI potential gets is five out
of five.  This means that
if we compare the plans on the basis of product benefits among all the plans available in the market, then
this plan will be among the top plans.  Right?
Aditya Birla is also got five out of
five.  So basically both the plans are very
good.  There is no issue in the plan.
Both plans are good and both are being
offered to you with very modern features.
Customer Service Rating 4.7 In case of ICICI
Potential Aditya Birla is at 5 out of
5.  So Aditya Birla is doing well even
in customer service.  ICIC potential is not
very far.  Right?  Claims Experience 4.9
in case of ICIC Potential, 4.4 in case of
Aditya Birla.  So claims, I was thinking
that maybe the claims would be good that is why the
premium of Aditya Birla would be so high.  But
ICICI potential is doing better even in
claims at 4.9 versus 4.4 for Aditya
Birla.  Overall Rating ICICI Potential 4.9
out of five.  A Aditya Birla Super Term
Plan 4.7 out of five.  So, clearly
ICICI Pen takes the lead in terms of all the
three parameters, product, customer service and
Aditya Birla is a little more.  And
again it takes the d in claims experience.
So, 4.9 is clearly the leader in overall rating.
So, ICIC Potential Wins the Race in
the Comparison That We Have Done.  Very very to
understand that this is done on a
standard persons metric.  That
we take one person.  Let us take a persona who is 30 years old.
He has to take a sum insurance
plan.  He needs these features.  That's the
Ye family.  This is his background.
This rating is done accordingly.  But when
you are sitting to make a plan, it is not necessary
that it should be the same person.  You are your own
needs.  You have your own
requirements.  You
need your own psychological comfort.  You
in such type of products.  That is why
we say that you should sit with a good expert and have a
one-to-one discussion and then
decide which plan you should take.
If you are looking for such experts and
no one is available in your circle then do come to them.  And we will
basically help you by connecting with
India's top insurance experts who we
screen and put on a platform.  These people are
not just any call center executives who are just
sitting there to push plans on you.  These are real
experts whom we have tested
for their knowledge, for their
processes, for their track record and
everything and then put on our platform.
The experts give you free consultation and they also
help you at the time of games.
If you are interested in this, there is
a link in the pin comment.  You
can use that.  There is also a link in the description,
you can use it to initiate your consultation.
Consultation is free
and we guarantee you no spam.  So that is what we
offer.  If there are any questions that we are not
able to answer in this video
please put it in the comments.  We will be more than
happy to answer them.  We will also learn
what we missed to
tell you in the video.  And if there is nothing except that, then there is nothing
except that.  If you liked this video
, you found this helpful
video and you found that the video
actually helps you understand these two
products well, then do like the video.  It
encourages us to do more and more videos.  It takes a lot of
hard work to make these videos.
So the team is involved in that video.  So
we get some encouragement by seeing the likes.
So If You Find The Video Helpful Do
Like Us.  Like the video and the last is
obviously subscribe to us if you want to see more such
videos.  Thank you very much.